[
  {
    "question": "What is the length of the WEP initialization vector (IV)?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": "2014 Fall",
    "options": ["24 bits", "32 bits", "48 bits", "64 bits"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main trick of the Beck & Tews chopchop-like attack on TKIP?",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": "2014 Fall",
    "options": [
      "An attacker can avoid the re-keying interval of the MIC failure report frame",
      "An attacker can get responses to packets sent with partly guessed content",
      "An attacker can cause packets to be silently dropped",
      "An attacker can decrypt the special packets received over QoS channels"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the \ffields of the 128-bit start value for RSN CCMP encryption?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "8-bit flag, 104-bit nonce, and a 16-bit counter; where the nonce fi\feld contains an 8-bit priority value, the 48-bit source address, and the 48-bit packet number",
      "16-bit fag, 104-bit nonce, and a 8-bit counter; where the nonce \ffield contains an 8-bit priority value, the 48-bit source address, and the 48-bit packet number",
      "The 16-bit packet number, and a 112-bit nonce value from a sequence counter",
      "128-bit random nonce value"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Extensible Authentication Protocol (EAP)?",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "EAP is a set of encapsulation messages for mutual authentication methods",
      "EAP is a set of encapsulation messages for upper-layer authentication methods",
      "EAP is a set of encapsulation messages for RSN authentication methods",
      "EAP is a set of encapsulation messages for RADIUS server authentication methods"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the inputs of the GSM authentication function A3?",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "<math><msub><mi>K</mi><mi>i</mi></msub></math> and <math><mi>RAND</mi></math> and <math><mi>XRES</mi></math>",
      "<math><mi>RAND</mi></math> and <math><mi>XRES</mi></math>",
      "<math><msub><mi>K</mi><mi>i</mi></msub></math> and <math><mi>XRES</mi></math>",
      "<math><msub><mi>K</mi><mi>i</mi></msub></math> and <math><mi>RAND</mi></math>"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of the sequence number (SQN) used in UMTS?",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Preventing man-in-the-middle attacks",
      "Preventing session hijacking",
      "Preventing replay attacks",
      "Enabling re-synchronization"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Is mutual authentication provided when a GSM SIM is used to access a UTRAN?",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Yes, between the MS and the RNC",
      "Yes, between the MS and the core network, but not the RNC",
      "No, the GSM SIM cannot authen\bticate the base station",
      "No, the GSM SIM cannot connect to a UTRAN"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the content and use of the UMTS AUTS parameter?",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "<math><mi>SQN</mi><mo>&#x2295;</mo><mi>AK</mi></math>, <math><mi>MAC-S</mi></math>. Resynchronization when the SQN check fails on the network side",
      "<math><mi>SQN</mi><mo>&#x2295;</mo><mi>CK</mi></math>, <math><mi>MAC-S</mi></math>. Resynchronization when the SQN check fails on the network side",
      "<math><mi>SQN</mi><mo>&#x2295;</mo><mi>AK</mi></math>, <math><mi>MAC-S</mi></math>. Resynchronization when the SQN check fails on the MS side",
      "<math><mi>SQN</mi><mo>&#x2295;</mo><mi>CK</mi></math>, <math><mi>MAC-S</mi></math>. Resynchronization when the SQN check fails on the MS side"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How is forward key separation achieved during handovers over X2 connections in EPS?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "The target eNB receives a fresh key from MME immediately after handover",
      "The target eNB receives a fresh key from MME right before handover",
      "The source eNB sends a derived key to the target eNB by applying a one-way function to the current key",
      "Forward key separation cannot be achieved, only backward key separation"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the speci\ffied length of the permanent subscriber key K in EPS/LTE?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": "2014 Fall",
    "options": [
      "No standard length specifi\fed",
      "128 bits",
      "192 bits",
      "256 bits"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The end points of user data encryption in EPS are",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": "2014 Fall",
    "options": [
      "The UICC and the eNB",
      "The UE and the MME",
      "The UE and the eNB",
      "The UICC and the MME"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The end points of signalling encryption in the EPS access stratum are",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "The UICC and the eNB",
      "The UE and the eNB",
      "The eNB and the MME",
      "The UE and the MME"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The end points of signalling integrity in the EPS non-stratum access are",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "The UICC and the eNB",
      "The UE and the eNB",
      "The eNB and the MME",
      "The UE and the MME"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Does EPS provide end-to-end data security?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "Yes, but only authenticity",
      "Yes, but only anonymity",
      "Yes, both confidentiality and authenticity"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the telecom practice of lawful interception?",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Dragnet surveillance secretly performed by an authorized intelligence agency",
      "Legal deep packet inspection and \ffiltering of mobile systems traffic",
      "Eavesdropping of private communication performed by the police",
      "Wiretapping of private communication requested by a law enforcement agency"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where does the key derivation function KDF of EPS reside?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "In the UICC and the HSS",
      "In the UICC and the UE",
      "In the UE and the MME",
      "In the UE and the AuC"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the three functional requirements for UMTS authentication?",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Con\ffindentiality and privacy for the subscriber, and mutual authentication for the service provider",
      "AV generation at AuC, key transport to the RNC, and the SQN synchronization",
      "Mutual authentication between USIM and HSS, securing the radio channel communication, and end-to-end confidentiality",
      "Mutual authentication between USIM and AuC, securing the radio channel communication, and user identity confidentiality"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why can the UICC be physically separated from the rest of the UE device?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "The UE manufacturing and lifecycle can be managed independently from the personalization and subscription process",
      "The UICC holds an expiration date and, like credit cards, must be replaced",
      "The failure rate of the integrated circuit cards (UICCs) are high because the issuers (mobile operators) want to optimize cost against subscription duration",
      "The manufacturer plugs a special key-card into the UICC interface slot for key distribution and software management"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the di\u000bfference between a checksum code and a cryptographic message authentication code?",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": "2014 Fall",
    "options": [
      "There is no di\u000bfference, they are only di\u000bfferent terms for the same primitive",
      "A message authentication code can be used to construct a checksum code, but not the other way around",
      "A checksum can be (re-)computed by an attacker, the authentication code cannot",
      "A keyed checksum provides stronger message integrity protection than a message authentication code"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What cipher mode of operation is specified in the Bluetooth Low Energy standard?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": "2014 Fall",
    "options": ["CCMP", "CBC", "E0", "BLE"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is ciphertext padding?",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Methods of adding false bits to a ciphertext packet",
      "Methods of making fi\fxed length ciphertext packets",
      "Methods of cryptanalysis using weak crypto-keys",
      "Methods of cryptanalysis using paper pads"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Are the GPS satellite signals protected cryptographically?",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "No protection because GPS receivers are keyless",
      "Partly, the military spread-spectrum code is encrypted",
      "By the distinct satellite signal authentication codes",
      "By a public key satellite identity authentication code"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which attack is prevented if an RFID tag can authenticate the reader?",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Tracking of the tag locations",
      "Tag blocking",
      "Tag inventory registration",
      "Illicit reading of the tag information"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an RFID tree-walking singulation protocol?",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "A privacy-preserving identi\fcation protocol where a tag releases its identity number bit by bit",
      "A disruption protocol by a blocker tag simulating a range of identities",
      "A reader initiated anti-collision protocol run when multiple tags respond simultaneously",
      "A reader monitoring protocol for discovering a given tag identity"
    ]
  }
]
